Carl Owen Dunbar Archives
Yale Peabody Museum of Natural History
Carl Owen Dunbar Archives
1914-1979
IPAR.001003
Yale Peabody Museum of Natural History
10
The archives consist of field notebooks from 1914-1957, photographs of both specimens and localities, inventories of specimens and localities, miscellaneous material gathered for notes and lectures, unpublished manuscripts, and correspondence. There are also hydrographic and topographic maps of Newfoundland, and topographic maps of Illinois, Nebraska, Oklahoma, New York, Texas, Pennsylvania, Arizona, Colorado, and Missouri.
Dunbar, Carl Owen, 1891-1979
Biographical Sketch
Carl Owen Dunbar (b. 1891, d. 1979) was born in Hallowell, Kansas. His parents, David and Emma (Thomas), lived on a wheat farm in southeastern Kansas. As a youth, he operated the power machinery used to plant and harvest wheat and served as the foreman on the ranch that was established by his grandfather, Warder Dunbar. He attended Cherokee County schools and graduated with honors. He received a B.A. degree from the University of Kansas in 1913 and a Ph.D. in geology from Yale University in 1917, and after a brief stay at the University of Minnesota, he returned to Yale in 1920 where he served with distinction for 39 years.
As a professor, Dunbar was a productive scholar, dedicated teacher and effective administrator. He published more than 200 scientific articles and monographs in invertebrate paleontology (particularly on brachiopods and fusulinids) and stratigraphy. His dedication to undergraduate teaching led him to write 3 textbooks on historical geology, first as a co-author with his mentor Charles Schuchert, and then with Karl Waage, his successor at Yale. Dunbar also wrote 2 textbooks on stratigraphy with Yale professor John Rogers.
During his tenure at Yale Dunbar supervised nearly 25 graduate students, many of whom continued to collaborate with him in the years that followed. As an administrator, Dunbar was also Curator of Invertebrate Paleontology at the Yale Peabody Museum and the Director of the Museum from 1942 until his retirement.
Description of the Material
Includes Dunbar's personal field notebooks from 1914-1957. Also, maps from his field areas, photographs of specimens and localities, and miscellaneous other material (both biographic and collections related).
Kansas; Connecticut; USA; Yale Peabody Museum; Yale University
- Field Notebooks, 1914-1957; Series I
  - 1914-1920., 001176
    - Notebook. Field Notebook: Iowa., 1914; 000006
    - Notebook. Field Notebook: Tennessee., 1916; 000007
    - Notebook. Field Notebook: Tennessee., 1916; 000008
    - Notebook. Field Notebook: Tennessee, Ohio, Washington, DC. 1917, 000009
    - Notebook. Field Notebook: Tennessee., 1917; 000010
    - Notebook. Field Notebook: Tennessee., 1917; 000011
    - Notebook. Field Notebook: Newfoundland., 1918; 000012
    - Notebook. Field Notebook: Newfoundland., 1918; 000013
    - Notebook. Field Notebook: Newfoundland., 1918; 000014
    - Notebook. Field Notebook: Newfoundland., 1918; 000015
    - Notebook. Field Notebook: Newfoundland., 1920; 000016
    - Notebook. Field Notebook: New York., 1920; 000017
    - Notebook. Field Notebook: New York., 1920; 000018
  - 1921-1930., 001177
    - Notebook. Field Notebook: Oklahoma., 1921; 000019
    - Notebook. Field Notebook: Kansas; Ohio., 1921; 000020
    - Notebook. Field Notebook: Kansas., 1921; 000021
    - Notebook. Field Notebook: Kansas., 1921; 000022
    - Notebook. Field Notebook: New York, Ontario., 1922; 000023
    - Notebook. Field Notebook: Vermont., 1922; 000037
    - Notebook. Field Notebook: Chicago, Illinois (Field Museum), Nebraska. This notebook includes Dunbar's visits to and thoughts about the Field Museum and the Historical Geology Hall at the University of Nebraska., 1923; 000024
    - Notebook. Field Notebook: Kansas, Nebraska, Iowa., 1924; 000025
    - Notebook. Field Notebook: Colorado, Nebraska, Kansas., 1924; 000026
    - Notebook. Field Notebook: Nebraska, Oklahoma, Kansas, Missouri., 1925; 000027
    - Notebook. Field Notebook: Iowa, South Dakota, Wyoming., 1926; 000028
    - Notebook. Field Notebook: Iowa, Kansas, Missouri, Nebraska, Ohio, Texas., 1926; 000029
    - Notebook. Field Notebook: Kansas, Nebraska, Oklahoma., 1927; 000030
    - Notebook. Field Notebook: Nebraska, Kansas, Missouri, Illinois., 1928; 000031
    - Notebook. Field Notebook: Colorado, Nebraska, South Dakota, Wyoming., 1929; 000032
  - 1931-1940., 001178
    - Notebook. Field Notebook: New York. 1931, 1955, 000033
    - Notebook. Field Notebook: Vermont., 1932; 000034
    - Notebook. Field Notebook: Newfoundland., 1933; 000035
    - Notebook. Field Notebook: Newfoundland., 1933; 000036
    - Notebook. Field Notebook: New York. 11/1933, 08/1939, 07/1948, 12/1948, 06/1949, 000045
    - Notebook. Field Notebook: New York. 1936, 1955, 000043
    - Notebook. pdfs of Dunbar's 1937 IGC field notebook and photo album, both held at the library of the University of Kansas. We only have these items as digital assets. Original photographs were taken by Una Farrell while she was collections manager there., 003222
    - Notebook. Field Notebook: Oklahoma, Texas., 1939; 000042
  - 1941-1950., 001179
    - Notebook. Field Notebook: Arizona, New Mexico, Texas., 1941; 000041
    - Notebook. Field Notebook: Illinois, New York, Pennsylvania. 1942, 1943. This notebook includes Dunbar's visits to and thoughts about the following museums: Museum of Natural History of the Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia, Buffalo Science Museum, Field Museum., 000040
    - Notebook. Field Notebook: New York., 1944; 000039
    - Notebook. Field Notebook: Kentucky, Maryland, Virginia, Tennessee. 09/1945; 1951, 000038
    - Notebook. Field Notebook: Pennsylvania, Virginia., 1948; 000049
    - Notebook. Field Notebook: Texas. 1949, 1955, 000046
    - Notebook. Field Notebook: New York. 1950, 1955, 1958, 1959. There is a thank you card inserted into this notebook and signed by John Burger, Brian Norford, Robert Green, Jon Rodgers, Billy Berry, and Dick Berry., 000044
    - Notebook. Field Notebook: Ohio, Pennsylvania, West Virginia., 1950; 000048
    - Notebook. Field Notebook: Texas., 1950; 000050
  - 1950-1957., 001180
    - Notebook. Field Notebook: New York. 1951?, 1952?, 000051
    - Notebook. Field Notebook & Strat. Secton: Missouri, Oklahoma. 1951, 1953, 000052
    - Notebook. Field Notebook: New York; Pennsylvania. 1952, 1953, 000053
    - Notebook. Field Notebook: Alabama, Maryland, Mississippi, New Jersey; and typed locality notes. 1955, 1957, 000054
    - Notebook. Field Notebook: Texas. 1956, 1957, 000047
    - Notebook. Field Notebook: Arizona.; Tyrrell base map of Whetstone Mtns., 1956; 000056
    - Notebook. Field Notebook: Mexico. LOST., 1956; 000335
    - Notebook. Field Notebook: New York., 1957; 000057
- Maps, Series II
  - Arizona., 001187
    - Topographic map. Benson, AZ 30' Quad. (1: 125000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1915; 001588
  - Colorado., 001188
    - Topographic map. Glenwood Springs, CO Quad. (1: 125000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1930; 001390
  - Highway Map. Highway map of multiple states., 001191
    - Highway map. Touring map of DE, MD, VA & WV (1: 79260). Rand McNally & Company: Highway, with localities, 1944; 001618
    - Photographs & Negatives. signed Black & White 8 X 10-inch photo taken August 1959 (age 68), 000696
    - Photographs. B & W photo and 35 mm slide: Field conference in Marathon, Texas that includes ? Fan, C.O. Dunbar, (W.H.? Mathews (III), H.B. Whittington, G.A. Cooper and N.D. Newell. B & W photo and 35 mm slide., 1950; 000543
  - Illinois. Maps of Illinois, a few show bordering states., 001181
    - Topographic map. Danville, IL-IN 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1900; 001402
    - Topographic map. Peoria, IL 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1905; 001420
    - Topographic map. Belleville, IL 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1907; 001395
    - Topographic map. West Frankfort, IL 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1909; 001422
    - Topographic map. Herrin, IL 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1910; 001412
    - Topographic map. Murphysboro, IL 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1910; 001418
    - Topographic map. Canton, IL 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1912; 001398
    - Topographic map. La Salle, IL 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1913; 001413
    - Topographic map. Baldwin, IL 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1914; 001394
    - Topographic map. Ottawa, IL 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1915; 001419
    - Topographic map. Renault, IL-MO 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1915; 001421
    - Topographic map. Campbell Hill, IL-MO 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1916; 001397
    - Topographic map. Edgington, IL 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1916; 001405
    - Topographic map. Equality, IL 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1916; 001406
    - Topographic map. Marseilles, IL 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1916; 001414
    - Topographic map. Brownfield, IL 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1917; 001396
    - Topographic map. Coulterville, IL 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1917; 001401
    - Topographic map. Morris, IL 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1918; 001417
    - Topographic map. Dongola, IL 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1920; 001403
    - Topographic map. Golcondia, KY-IL 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1921; 001389
    - Topographic map. Carbondale, IL 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1922; 001399
    - Topographic map. Monmouth, IL 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1923; 001416
    - Topographic map. Alexis, IL 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1925; 001392
    - Topographic map. Havana, IL 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1925; 001410
    - Topographic map. Harrisburg, IL 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1925; 001411
    - Topographic map. Marion, IL 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1925; 001415
    - Topographic map. Winchester, IL 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1926; 001423
    - Topographic map. Alton, IL-MO Quad. (1: 48000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1927; 001393
    - Topographic map. Galesburg, IL 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1927; 001407
    - Topographic map. Glasford, IL 15.0 Quad. (1: 48000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1927; 001408
    - Topographic map. Greenfield, IL 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1932; 001409
    - Topographic map. French Village, IL 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1935; 001404
    - Topographic map. Chester, IL-MO 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1947; 001400
  - Missouri., 001189
    - Topographic map. Saint Louis, MO-IL 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1904; 001391
  - Nebraska., 001182
    - Geologic map. NW Quay County, NE, Geology of (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Geologic, 1946; 002296
    - Soil map. Gage County [NE], NE Soil Map (1: 63420). Gage County, NE: Soil., 1914; 001426
    - Topographic map. Freemont, NE 30.0 Quad. (1: 125000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1896; 001425
    - Topographic map. Linclon, NE 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1897; 001432
    - Topographic map. Grand Island, NE 30.0 Quad. (1: 125000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1898; 001427
    - Topographic map. Omaha And Vicinity, NE (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1898; 001436
    - Topographic map. Weeping Water, NE 30.0 Quad. (1: 125000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1903; 001437
    - Topographic map. Nebrasca City, NE 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1907; 001433
    - Topographic map. Falls City, NE 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1915; 001424
    - Topographic map. Howe, NE 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1915; 001429
    - Topographic map. Humbolt, NE 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1915; 001430
    - Topographic map. Nemaha, NE 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1915; 001434
    - Topographic map. Humbolt, NE 15 Quad (1: 125000), U.S. Geological Survey, topographic., 1916; 001431
    - Topographic map. Ogala, NE 30.0 Quad. (1: 125000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1922; 001435
  - New York., 001184
    - Geologic map. Catskill & Kaaterskill, NY 15 Quad. (1: 62500) spliced together. U.S. Geological Survey: Geologic., 1936; 002220
    - Topographic map. Schuylerville, NY 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic. 1900 (1931), 002032
    - Topographic map. Morrisville, NY 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500) U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic. 1902 (1948), 002015
    - Topographic map. Norwich, NY 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500) U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic. 1903 (1921), 002017
    - Topographic map. Newburgh, NY 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic. 1903 (1936), 002031
    - Topographic map. Kaaterskill, NY 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic. 1903 (1932), 002033
    - Topographic map. Rosendale, NY 15 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1903; 002081
    - Topographic map. Sangerfield, NY 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500) U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic. 1907 (1942), 002019
    - Topographic map. Hartwick, NY 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500) U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1910; 002014
    - Topographic map. New Berlin, NY 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500) U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic. 1912 (1944), 002016
    - Topographic map. Oneida, NY 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500) U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1946; 002018
    - Topographic map. Earlville, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 25000). U.S. Geological Surrvey.: Topographic., 1949; 002020
    - Topographic map. Hamilton, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 25000). U.S. Geological Surrvey.: Topographic., 1949; 002021
    - Topographic map. Hubbardsville, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 25000). U.S. Geological Surrvey.: Topographic., 1949; 002022
    - Topographic map. Morrisville, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 25000). U.S. Geological Surrvey.: Topographic., 1949; 002023
    - Topographic map. Munnsville, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 25000). U.S. Geological Surrvey.: Topographic., 1949; 002024
    - Topographic map. Oriskany Falls, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 25000). U.S. Geological Surrvey.: Topographic., 1949; 002025
    - Topographic map. Sherburne, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 25000). U.S. Geological Surrvey.: Topographic., 1949; 002026
    - Topographic map. West Eaton, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 25000). U.S. Geological Surrvey.: Topographic., 1949; 002027
  - Newfoundland., 001190
    - Geologic map. Geological Map of Newfoundland. U.S. Hydrographic Office: Geologic., 1919; 001665
    - Hydrographic map. West & South Coasts of Newfoundland. U.S. Hydrographic Office: Hydrographic., 1888; 001647
    - Hydrographic map. West Coast of Newfoundland. U.S. Hydrographic Office: Hydrographic., 1889; 001636
    - Hydrographic map. Pistolet Bay, Newfoundland (1: 42946). U.S. Hydrographic Office: Hydrographic., 1892; 001662
    - Hydrographic map. Bonne Bay, Newfoundland. U.S. Hydrographic Office: Hydrographic., 1895; 001660
    - Hydrographic map. Bonne Bay, Newfoundland. U.S. Hydrographic Office: Hydrographic., 1895; 001661
    - Hydrographic map. Codroy Road to Bear Head, Newfoundland. U.S. Hydrographic Office: Hydrographic., 1896; 001644
    - Hydrographic map. Savage Cove to St. Barbe Bay, Newfoundland (1: 21140). U.S. Hydrographic Office: Hydrographic., 1898; 001648
    - Hydrographic map. Bonne Bay, Newfoundland. U.S. Hydrographic Office: Hydrographic., 1903; 001639
    - Hydrographic map. Woody Point Anchorage, Neddy Harbor, Newfoundland. U.S. Hydrographic Office: Hydrographic., 1903; 001640
    - Hydrographic map. Rouche (Rocky) Harbor, Newfoundland. U.S. Hydrographic Office: Hydrographic., 1903; 001642
    - Hydrographic map. North and East Coasts of Newfoundland. U.S. Hydrographic Office: Hydrographic., 1906; 001664
    - Hydrographic map. Pistolet Bay, Newfoundland (1: 39028). U.S. Hydrographic Office: Hydrographic., 1909; 001634
    - Hydrographic map. Hawke Bay to Ste. Genevieve Bay, Newfoundland (1: 72960). U.S. Hydrographic Office: Hydrographic., 1913; 001643
    - Hydrographic map. Hawke Bay to Ste. Genevieve Bay, Newfoundland (1: 73539). U.S. Hydrographic Office: Hydrographic., 1915; 001649
    - Hydrographic map. Hare Bay, Newfoundland. U.S. Hydrographic Office: Hydrographic., 1915; 001656
    - Hydrographic map. Hawke Bay to Ste. Genevieve Bay, Newfoundland (1: 73539). U.S. Hydrographic Office: Hydrographic., 1915; 001663
    - Hydrographic map. Hare Bay, Newfoundland. U.S. Hydrographic Office: Hydrographic., 1916; 001657
    - Hydrographic map. Hare Bay, Newfoundland. U.S. Hydrographic Office: Hydrographic., 1916; 001658
    - Hydrographic map. Ste. Geneveive Bay to Orange Bay & the Stra..., Newfoundland U.S. Hydrographic Office: Hydrographic., 1917; 001646
    - Hydrographic map. Saint Margeret Bay and Approaches, Newfoundland. U.S. Hydrographic Office: Hydrographic., 1917; 001651
    - Hydrographic map. North & East Coasts of Newfoundland. U.S. Hydrographic Office: Hydrographic., 1917; 001653
    - Hydrographic map. St. Julien I. to Hooping Harbor, Newfoundland (1: 73342). U.S. Hydrographic Office: Hydrographic., 1917; 001655
    - Hydrographic map. Port Au Port, Newfoundland. U.S. Hydrographic Office: Hydrographic., 1918; 001652
    - Hydrographic map. Cow Head Harbor, Shallow Bay & Cow Cove, Newfoundland (1: 15855). U.S. Hydrographic Office: Hydrographic., 1919; 001638
    - Hydrographic map. Bonne Bay to the Burgeo Islands, Newfoundland (1: 293798). U.S. Hydrographic Office: Hydrographic., 1922; 001645
    - Hydrographic map. West Coast of Newfoundland. U.S. Hydrographic Office: Hydrographic., 1923; 001637
    - Hydrographic map. West Coast of Newfoundland (1: 282196). U.S. Hydrographic Office: Hydrographic., 1923; 001654
    - Hydrographic map. Current Island to Bird Cove, Newfoundland (1: 16925). U.S. Hydrographic Office: Hydrographic., 1929; 001650
    - Hydrographic map. Index map of northeast Canada. U.S. Hydrographic Office: Hydrographic., 001633
    - Topographic map. Bear Head to Cow Head, Newfoundland (1: 42440). U.S. Hydrographic Office: Hydrographic., 1900; 001635
    - Topographic map. Bay of Islands, Lark Harbor, Newfoundland, U.S. Hydrographic Office: Hydrographic., 1903; 001641
    - Topographic map. Approach to Strait of Belle Isle, Newfoundland. U.S. Hydrographic Office: Hydrographic., 1913; 001659
  - Oklahoma., 001183
    - Topographic map. Atoka, OK 30.0 Quad. (1: 125000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1900; 001438
    - Topographic map. Ardmore, OK 30.0 Quad. (1: 125000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1901; 001440
    - Topographic map. Stonewall, OK 30.0 Quad. (1: 125000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1901; 001444
    - Topographic map. Tishomino, OK 30.0 Quad. (1: 125000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1901; 001445
    - Topographic map. Coalgate, OK 30.0 Quad. (1: 125000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1909; 001441
    - Topographic map. McAlester, OK 30.0 Quad. (1: 125000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1909; 001442
    - Topographic map. Tuskahoma, OK 30.0 Quad. (1: 125000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1909; 001446
    - Topographic map. Red Oak, OK 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1943; 001443
  - Pennsylvania., 001186
    - Topographic map. Pottsville, PA 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic. 1891 (1909), 002035
    - Topographic map. Easton, PA-NJ 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic. 1891 (1913), 002037
    - Topographic map. Allentown, PA 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic. 1894 (1912), 002036
    - Topographic map. Slatington, PA 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic. 1902 (1912), 002034
  - Texas., 001185
    - Topographic map. Abilene 30' Quad (1: 125000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1894; 001587
    - Topographic map. Tahlequah 30' Quad. (1: 125000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1901; 001578
    - Topographic map. Guadalupe Peak, TX 15.0 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1940; 002069
    - Topographic map. Guadalupe Peak, TX 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1973; 002070
    - Topographic map. Old Blue Mountain, TX 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1983; 002111
    - Topographic map. Dugout Mountain, TX 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1983; 002112
    - Topographic map. Glass Mountain Ranch, TX 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 002103
    - Topographic map. Wolf Camp Hills, TX 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 002104
    - Topographic map. Leonard Mountain, TX 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 002105
    - Topographic map. Sierra Madera, TX 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 002106
    - Topographic map. Marathon Gap, TX 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 002107
    - Topographic map. Dimple Hills, TX 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 002108
    - Topographic map. Cap Rock Butte, TX 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 002109
    - Topographic map. Reininger Draw, TX 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 002110
- Photographs, Series II
  - Localities., 001192
    - Photographs & Negatives. Black and white prints and slides of fusulines from Illinois Black and white prints, negatives, 1942; 000582
    - Photographs & Negatives. Three black and white prints (7x9, 5x9, 4x2) of YPM 6657, Olenellus getzi. Black and white print., 000567
    - Photographs & Negatives. Black and white prints of fusulinids from Russia prints, 000575
    - Photographs & Negatives. Black and white glass negatives of Pennsylvanian fusulines from Nebraska, 000592
    - Photographs & Negatives. Black and white glass negatives of Pennsylvania fusulines from Nebraska, 000593
    - Photographs & Negatives. Black and white prints and negatives of Pennsylvanian fusulinids from New Mexico, Colorado, Nevada and China Black and white prints, 000601
    - Photographs & Negatives. Glass negatives of fusulinids from India, Pennsylvanian, Permian, 000852
    - Photographs & Negatives. Glass negatives a n prints of fusulinids, Salt Range, India, Pennsylvanian, Permian, 000853
    - Slides. 35 mm black & white, & color slides; Permian, Glass Mtns area, Texas; New York; Tennessee; Virginia; England; Russia: fusulinids. 35 mm slides, b & w, & color. 1940-1960, 000751
  - Specimens., 001193
    - Negatives and photographs. Black and white negatives and prints of nautiloids from the Ordovician of Newfoundland., 002426
- Miscellaneous, Series IV
  - Collection Information. Collection lists, notes and inventories., 001195
    - Faunal list. Faunal list: New York., 1934; 000371
    - Papers, notes, correspondence. Correspondence, memo's and notes of a committee or program to evaluate the potential of Arctic research for the Arctic Institute of North America, 1950; 000712